Good morning and happy Friday. You're
watching the program with Ted Rall and
John Kiriakou as John and I brace for
the big snowstorm. Seriously, man.
I Did I tell you night before last my
son and I went to Home Depot?
I I can't find my scraper for my
windshield. Oh, I always lose those. I
must have like five of them, seriously.
>> they're probably buried in the back
recesses of your trunk under [__]
>> probably are. So So we went to to Target
and Target that the shelves were
literally bare. It was like It was like
COVID all over again. So it's just
diagonally from across the street from
the Home Depot. So we went there. And
mind you, this is
This is like 9:00 on a Wednesday night.
We couldn't find a parking space
at the Home Depot, first of all.
So we had to park where they have sort
of taken the parking spaces and they use
it for storage. You know how Home Depots
do? Yeah. So we went in and there's a
guy holding a container of of salt,
rock salt,
and I said, "Excuse me, can you tell me
where you got the salt?" He said, "Very
back of aisle four, and you better get
back there fast."
>> [laughter]
>> We were like, "What?" So we ran back
there. It's a mob of people, and as
quickly as this poor hapless like
70-year-old stock clerk
is pulling the salt out of the boxes,
people are just grabbing them out of his
hand.
So I got three containers, three 8-lb
containers,
and they're in my trunk. I gave my son
one. I'm going to give a friend of mine
one, and I've got one for my car just in
case. But man, and the models are
different. I mentioned yesterday, they
haven't changed at least this morning
when I first woke up, they hadn't
changed. But it was um
the American model and the American AI
model are saying um
8 to 12 inches for us, but then the
European model
is saying
um
uh 20 21 to 26 inches.
Yeah, let me look right now.
Uh yeah, we're looking now at at 8 to
10, according to the
>> we know which which one Do you happen to
know which one tends to be more
accurate?
I remember downloading this one because
the other one was inaccurate. So I'm
going to say 8 to 10, 8 to 12.
And we'll see.
>> swear by AccuWeather. It's my It's my
favorite weather app.
>> Yeah. Um you know, I like I mean, it's
it's almost unearthly. It'll
>> Oh, this is the Weather Channel.
>> It'll say like, you know, "Snow stops in
17 minutes." And then it does, yeah.
Okay, I'm going to I'm going to download
it right now. So I think we're expecting
over a foot um I guess 1 foot and 4
inches in New York City um and more in
the surrounding areas, and it's going to
be coupled with ice and
severe cold temperatures.
Um you know, it's going to be wind
chills tonight of below zero in New York
City
uh and actual temperatures of like
single digits in New York City like over
the weekend. We have um
uh low of 17, high of 18.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, at least you know what the
temperature's going to be. It's not one
of those like, "Oh, like California,
like we need layers." Yeah, no, not not
so much.
Um
well, it's going to it's uh it's cold in
Gaza, but Jared Kushner thinks it's
going to be hotter. We'll We'll talk
about that uh and how exactly this is
going to look. You mentioned this
yesterday, and I did a deeper dive over
overnight into Jared Kushner's vision
for Club Med Gaza. Uh
Minneapolis is is uh I didn't know this
was coming. Uh this kind of snuck up on
me. It snuck up on me, too. I actually
didn't know it was coming. There's a
citywide strike. Um hundreds of
businesses are going to close down
today. Um thousands, maybe tens of
thousands of Minneapolitans, is that
what you call them? I don't know what
you call them. Um are going to be uh are
not are going to refuse to work today.
Um ICE is already complaining that they
can't get hotel rooms. Their hotel room
reservations get canceled. Uh their uh
you know, they can't get a cup of
coffee. They're refused service. Um oh,
sad It's sad to be a you know, sadistic
macho steroided [__] Um and uh
Trump is turning to the left. We already
kind of knew this like 2 weeks ago when
he was talking to Elizabeth Warren. But
he's looking to the left uh on the
economy. I have thoughts about that. Um
and the Department of Homeland Security
kind of pulled like what Time magazine
did to O.J. Simpson when they darkened
his picture for the cover. Uh they this
one of the three women who were
who were arrested for um
being in a protest against an ICE
preacher, that those are the two words
that I'd go that would go there. Um
is uh that one of them they they tweeted
out her picture. It was modified by AI
to make it look like she was crying and
blacker than she is.
>> Right. So um all beautiful stuff. And of
course, obviously, please like, follow,
share the show.
Um we appreciate your donations as
always. We're I think it's fair to say,
John, we're we're now actually, we you
know, we can see the light at the end of
the tunnel, and it doesn't seem to be a
train heading to run us over. Amen. Yes.
It was doing well now. And Yeah, and
thanks to everybody.
Yeah. Thanks to everybody because when
we first started this, remember we
started it with Michelle.
Um and uh
and I think we had five people watch the
first episode, literally. Quite
literally.
>> that's right. And And we appreciate
those five people.
>> We do, very much, because we it was it
was from that that we grew. And uh and
now we're able to, you know, actually
pay the electric bill.
Which was a concern for a while.
Oh, yeah, yeah, no, for sure. And we
have questions in the feeds. So, you
know, maybe we could do what we did
yesterday, John, and knock out knock out
a story or two and then get to the
questions. What do you think? That
sounds like a plan.
All right. I'm I'm interested in all of
these things, but you
you get to pick.
Okay. Um
let's talk about Minneapolis. I I was
invited to a dinner last night
uh
with Ilhan Omar. There were about 20 of
us.
And she talked about this uh this really
what amounts to a general strike in
Minneapolis today.
And she said something that I thought
was important.
Um Well, she said a couple of things
that I thought were important. That the
administration has
underestimated the resolve of
Minnesotans
repeatedly.
>> [snorts]
>> And she also said
These are sturdy people. It's routinely
20 below zero there. She That was an
important point that she made.
That these these ICE people from DC or
from where they wherever they are, Texas
or California, they're they're not used
to Minnesota winters.
And this is going to get very old for
them very quickly.
And um
you know, to use a line from The
Sopranos, from the Pine Barrens episode,
Minnesotans wash their balls with snow.
So [laughter]
Minnesotans aren't afraid of these uh of
these ICE people in this weather, number
one. Number two,
um
Minnesotans see this as a legit attack,
a federal attack on their city and
state. And they're not going to roll
over for it.
So this is going to get worse before it
gets better. She said that that the
federal government thought people were
just going to roll over, they were going
to run from the screaming from the room,
hide in their homes. That's not it at
all. She said that there are thousands
of people
who are
at least temporarily hiding people in
their homes
so that they can't be found.
Which is taking a Which is taking a
risk. Um that's a felony. It's a felony.
God bless them.
>> a felony your sentence.
>> God bless their sentence.
>> God bless them is right. You know, I've
said many times, many members of my
family came here as what people call
illegal immigrants.
And all they ever wanted to do was to
make money to to care for their
families. They were very happy to pay
taxes. They didn't come in legally, as
Robbie would complain,
uh because that option was not open to
them. Right. They couldn't come here
legally. The answer was no, we're not
giving visas to Greeks in the post-World
War II era. No.
And so, you know, I think that she made
a couple of good points last night that
that the administration isn't really
paying much attention to.
Um you you know, it's I think it's
always interesting um you get into
trouble politically
when you grind up against um a local
indigenous culture. Um I was thinking
about uh you know, Chris Christie was a
really unpopular governor of New Jersey.
And he pulled a lot of [__] as governor.
Yeah, he did. But what did him in
ultimately was two things, right? Once
One was [__] with something near and
dear to New Jerseyans, which is their
ability to commute in and out of New
York City.
Um that's why he lived in New Jersey.
Yes, and and so he did Bridgegate,
closing the George Washington
effectively closing the George
Washington Bridge. By the way, a lady
died
in an ambulance trying to
uh you know, on that day. That's right.
And then, worst of all, in the middle of
a heat wave, um closing all the beaches
but going to the beach himself with his
family. Again, New Jersey has a lot of
beach communities, and people really
value their you know, they're like, "We
might not live in a in a state that has
its own TV station, but we live in a
state that has beautiful beaches, and
all of us are No one's more than an hour
or an hour and 15 minutes away from a
beach. Um and he's taking that away from
us, and he's using it for himself. [__]
you. And this is similar. I mean, many
Minneapolitans and Minnesotans, you
know, we've all heard the term Minnesota
nice and it's it's a real thing. These
are to a fault hopelessly polite people.
You know, they're Scandinavian
ethnically most of the the whites are
and and that's the culture that sort of,
you know, everybody who moves there kind
of has to adapt to
regardless of their own ethnic
background. They're
and and they real and you know how it
is. Like New Yorkers don't care if
you're a little gruff, but like, you
know, Minnesotans, if you're if you're
like that, you know, if you're rude and
crude, people hate you. And and and
that's the exact impression that ICE
made. They culturally could not have
asked for a a worst more grading crash
seriously to say.
Seriously, I couldn't agree more.
Um
that's why I think this is going to be a
bigger deal than the government
realizes. And it's not like, you know,
they're planning to pull out on Tuesday.
This is an ongoing thing.
J.D. Vance kind of you know, kind of
tipped, you know, he's a smart guy. He
can, you know, he takes the temperature.
He knows what's up and he said, you
know, we want to turn down the
temperature. Well, that's a new
statement from the administration.
They've been
they've been turning up the temperature
all the way to like 600 and now,
you know, but the thing is they're not
doing the things that are required to to
turn down the temperature. Just saying
you want to turn it down doesn't do
anything. Um I guess this brings up the
issue of the
of the Homeland Security Twitter
account. I mean, which by the way is a
cesspool of like, you know,
alt-right, you know, wink wink nod nod
to like neo-Nazism
and you know, sort of crazy like memes
that look like they come out, you know,
Norman Rockwellish kind of 1930s like,
you know, not that he Norman Rockwell
was a right-winger far from it. But
that kind of idealized all white
American vision.
But anyway, they they they tweeted out a
picture altered of one of the three
women who
they arrested at for
disturbing the peace, I guess basically.
I think they're all going to walk, no
question.
You know, for basically yelling at this
ICE preacher for being member of ICE
during a church service, right?
I can't see what where the where the
lawbreaking is here unless you break a
You can't charge someone with
trespassing. Listen, I've become a
a YouTube expert on this kind of thing.
You can't charge someone with the crime
of trespassing until you have trespassed
to them. Which means you have to give
them written notification that they are
not permitted on your property.
Somebody you can't just
arrest somebody and charge them with
trespassing because they walk into a
church and start yelling.
You can throw them out. empire law rule
where I uninvite you and they fly out
the door. Exactly. Exactly. Um yeah, no,
so so the so this woman, right? I mean,
first of all, even if they had tweeted
out her photograph, I mean, this is an
agency that complains about federal
employees, ICE officers being doxxed,
right? By by leftist activists. Here
they are doxxing a you know, a private
citizen, right? A
a person of color, a woman on top of it.
So that would make that makes me really
uncomfortable. But on top of that, they
altered the image to look at make it
look like she was in tears. She wasn't.
>> She wasn't. And you know, she was brave
and composed and she and they made her
they they changed the color of her skin.
They tinted her to make her look more to
make her look darker.
Um this is racist. It's a racist it's a
racist thing to do. Just racist. The
Kristi Noem owes her and the country an
apology. Yeah.
Couldn't agree more. And this is not
turning down the temperature. Do you
remember of course of course you
remember
the [__] that Time magazine took when
they darkened O.J. Simpson's
booking picture his his mugshot. Yeah.
They had to make an apology and they
said that it was, you know, it was a
poorly thought out attempt to make it
look more stark and yeah.
I actually knew the editor who approved
that image at Time magazine because I
was doing cartoons there at at the time.
Oh. And [snorts] it did turn out to be
kind of a production [__] Um and
which, you know, people people don't
know like when you produce something in
a magazine like they you have to create
what they call a match print. You're not
really sure what it's going to look like
until it rolls off the press and you
kind of need to print so anyway, they
apparently they were late that day
because of the O.J. story. So they
didn't have time to do a match proof and
then the thing it's actually a
fascinating story. It's sort of like the
the Dean scream. Yeah.
>> knew someone who was working at his
campaign. The mic was malfunctioning
that night and when Howard Dean was
like, you know, shouting or trying to
he was trying yeah, he was trying to
make his mic work and it kind of played
into this awkward kind of you know,
image that the that the corporate media
was trying to to paint of him.
>> I I always liked him. Oh, I'm a big fan
and the 50 state the 50 state um
uh strategy is the way to go for any
party.
>> Absolutely. Oh my god. See, the Clintons
did this to the Democratic Party.
Because it was James Carville who
insisted on a 50 state uh strategy. Mhm.
This is something this is not a new
idea. This is something that George
McGovern proposed in 1960
when he first ran for the Senate. Um and
that's why the Democrats were able to
elect senators from North and South
Dakota, from Wyoming, from Oklahoma,
from Utah.
I mean, they were Democratic senators.
You don't write off entire sections of
the country. No, and what the Clintons
did was they ended
financing for Democratic candidates at
the state representative level.
>> Mhm.
Which controls redistricting in most
states.
>> And also it killed their farm system,
right? Somewhere somewhere in some
statehouse there's a there's some lady
who could be the president of the United
States in 40 years. That's right. But
you know, you don't we don't know that
because yeah, cuz she's not going to get
any money. She'll be defeated by a
Republican.
Um
yeah, no, it's it's really boneheaded
for a variety of reasons. We could do an
entire show on that. All right, let me
see about getting into so Robbie is just
getting just getting to us. So I'm going
to please bear with me guys while I
parse through the comments here. Much
appreciated.
Um
K. dot I'm going to sort of work through
these on YouTube. Ted, you mentioned
that one day you'd like a good
documentary to tell your story one day.
The first name and channel that came to
mind when I heard that was Andrew from
Channel 5 News.
Uh okay. Um I don't know who that is,
but
So like um if anyone wants to contact
me, it's rawl.com/contact.
Nicholas Francos, John, can you expect
explain a little bit about the situation
with the stateless people in Kuwait?
When I was studying for my bachelor's
degree, I met two girls. They said they
were refugees from Kuwait.
Kuwaiti citizenship is a difficult
thing.
Um there are multiple levels of Kuwaiti
citizenship. Three.
There are first class Kuwaitis.
>> [snorts]
>> Second class and third class. Now, a
first class Kuwaiti
is a descendant of someone who can trace
his
Kuwaiti citizenship to the census of
1920.
Right? So they had this big census in
1920. If you want to be Kuwaiti, come
and sign up.
Well, a lot of people didn't bother cuz
they were like, what is this state? This
we're Bedouins. Everything is our state.
We just move from place to place. This
was created by the by the by the Treaty
of Versailles? No, it coincided with the
Treaty of Versailles. Okay.
Second class Kuwaitis are descendants of
people who can trace their lineage to
people who were in Kuwait in 1920 but
didn't register.
Okay? Okay. Third class Kuwaitis are
people who have been granted Kuwaiti
citizenship
for whatever reason. You served the
royal the ruling family, you did some
special thing.
But who do not have the privileges of
first and second class citizenship. And
then there are stateless people called
Bedoon. Bedoon
in Arabic means without. So they are
without papers, without citizenship.
That's not the same word as Bedouin.
No.
It comes from the same root to move.
Badana to move around. Mhm. So Bedouins
kind of go through the desert, Kuwait,
Saudi Arabia, Iraq. They're constantly
nomads. They're moving from oasis to
oasis with their flocks.
But the Bedoon
tend to, you know, live in Kuwait City
like everybody else does. They just
don't have a passport. They don't have
any rights. They have to travel on
United Nations issued laissez-passers.
And so
like uh
like these two girls apparently um
you get a laissez-passer that allows you
to to travel the United States to go to
school, but you are not a Kuwaiti
citizen.
Huh.
Okay. It's rough. All right, Sneaker Dad
10 20. Thanks for the 10 bucks and thank
very much much appreciated.
Did you see Vance's talk yesterday? So
much us versus them, Katie catastrophe,
red versus blue. It was sickening
sickening. Well, that's it is sickening.
I you know, I mean,
very clearly this administration
repeatedly, you know, says the quiet
part out loud, which is if If you're not
a Republican and you're not a supporter
of President Trump, we don't care about
you. Um we don't care if you live or
die. Um I guess
the question for me, and I don't know I
really don't know the answer to this,
does this make Republicans or Trump
supporters uncomfortable or do they love
it? That's a good question.
That's a good question. I I don't know,
but you know what though? Even if it did
make them uncomfortable, they would
remain silent. We're not yet at a at a
point We're starting to get to this
point in the Senate, but we're not yet
at a point where people are comfortable
enough criticizing Donald Trump. Once we
get past the next election in November
and Trump truly is a lame duck cuz he's
not running for a third term. I don't
care what he says.
Um then I think people will feel much
more comfortable in um
criticizing him. Hey, let me add one
other thing.
Um Ilhan Omar mentioned last night at
this dinner that she had just come from
a series of budget votes on Capitol
Hill. We got We were getting push
notifications last night. So what the
Democrats did cuz they're utter and
complete and total sellouts
um is
they um they demanded that the budget
for Department of Homeland Security be
stripped out of the omnibus.
So she called it a mini bus, which I had
never heard before. It was kind of
funny.
So
All All the Yeah, all the Democrats
voted for the mini bus which funded the
the entire government except Homeland
Security.
But the Republicans were unified on the
Homeland Security vote last night. And
there were
just enough by like by like a majority
of two or three
that they approved the Homeland Security
uh budget, which includes ICE, of
course. And she And she said that
the only hope that the Democrats have to
either block the DHS budget or to shut
down the government again
is on the Senate side. She said the
Republicans are nowhere near
60 votes necessary to break cloture.
So I said, "Are you predicting
a government shutdown
brought by the Democrats?"
And she said, "Not necessarily." She
said because many of my Democratic
colleagues on the second side are
sellouts and weaklings.
So we'll see what happens. Nobody's
reporting this yet that there's a a real
possibility of another government
shutdown.
Uh when? March something. I would love
to see some [__] discipline inside
the Democratic caucus. It's chaos. It's
chaos in the Democratic caucus.
>> Jeffries was basically like, "I will
kick your ass so far down the street if
you stray from our party's official
position, you won't even [__]
remember." Um but yeah, that's we're not
there obviously and it's not going to
happen. Good question for you, John. I
I'm curious about this. Per Avida, John,
if an ex-source ever an ex-source ever
hit you up asking to meet up and talk
about life, would you follow up? Or the
curiosity not worth the risk or is it
simply just not allowed?
I absolutely would. I actually have. Ah.
Uh on two occasions.
One time I ran into one of my sources
an Iraqi
in Dulles Airport here in Washington. He
says to me, "John! John!" like that. And
I looked and I go
>> [laughter and gasps]
>> I go, "Mohammed?
What are you doing here?" He said, "I
became a refugee and now I'm an American
citizen." I was like, "Oh my god!" We
sat and had coffee and it dawned on me
partway through the conversation. I
said, "Wait a minute. You're speaking
English."
And he's like, "Yeah, I learned how to
speak English." It's just
It didn't register in my brain
that he was speaking
>> you see someone out of context, I guess
it's a more extreme version of like when
I see my dry cleaning dude at like the
bar. And I'm like, "Wait, you live at
the dry cleaner? I don't understand."
>> Exactly. Oh my god, I was at I was at
the the town mall in Newcastle,
Pennsylvania one time with my mom. I was
16 and there was this uh
We're not allowed to use the word [__]
anymore. What do we say? Short person?
Little person?
>> There was a little person. And
we're walking down the you know, middle
of the mall and he goes, "Hey, how you
doing?" I said, "Hey, how are you?"
And my mom goes, "How in the world do
you know that guy?"
And I said, "Oh, I He must have confused
me with somebody else." The truth is
that he was the bartender at the bar
that served minors that my buddies and I
used to go buy [laughter] six-packs
at City Lights Cafe. Anyway, God bless
those people. I remember when I my first
day at college um in 1981 in New York,
the drinking age was 18 at at Columbia.
I sidle up to the bar. And there's like
three like girls from like New Jersey
drinking and they're all like They
couldn't None of them could have been
older than 12. So I [laughter] I was The
bartender was flirting with me. And
she's like 40 and uh and and I go,
"What's up with the uh you know, what
about what what's with these ladies?"
And she goes, "I know you're new you're
new to New York City." She's like, "If
you're old enough to pay, you're old
enough to drink." City Lights Cafe, man.
And and occasionally Hanging Gardens uh
Bar and Lounge.
Hanging Gardens was good, but there was
a bartender there that that knew my
parents, so I tried to stay away.
>> [laughter]
>> And in Dayton where I grew up, we had
the best names for bars that they had
plausible deniability. Nowhere. Hey,
where have you been? Nowhere. Um the
library.
>> [laughter]
>> There was a whole row of bars like that
on Dixie Highway in Kettering, Ohio. Oh
my god. Anyway, so
let's see. Uh John, you've mentioned on
several podcasts, this is from K. Dot,
that you like to visit cemeteries a lot
during your spare time as part of your
writing process. Have you ever had a
paranormal or ghost encounter
while there? No, that's a fun question.
That's a very good question.
>> I I never have.
I I I was walking through uh Columbia
Gardens Cemetery here near my house um
one one night. It was nighttime, like
legit dark.
But
I mean, there's no reason to be afraid
at night in a cemetery and I heard this
screaming
that scared the [__] out of me. And it
turned out that there's a den of foxes
that lives in the uh
that lives in the uh cemetery and they
were fighting. That's all it was. But
no, I've never had a paranormal
experience in the cemetery. Foxes make
Foxes are are Foxes are so cool. I love
them.
>> Yeah, we have so many of them around
here and they like walk right up to you.
They're not afraid or anything.
>> Do you have red and black foxes?
We have both. Okay.
>> Most Mostly red. I see mostly red ones.
Thanks for the two bucks on on Pat.
Um
Okay. Angela Falla la I'm sure I think
this is for you I'm pretty sure this is
for you, John. Thanks for the fiver. Um
have you ever met Evy Pom
Pomporos? Former Secret Service now all
over YouTube and Greek like you. Yeah,
I've seen her
I've seen her in church a couple of
times.
She's She's quite good. She's very very
bright.
She was a Secret Service agent for I
don't know
12, 15 years.
Um
I remember she took a lot of [__] from
the the male Secret Service agents. They
were real jerks to her. She left to
become an author and a journalist and
her book was quite well received. It was
kind of a combination memoir
um self-help book. I don't remember the
name of it, but but it was quite well
received and now she's out on the
speaking circuit all the time.
And she's she's she's done well for
herself.
Uh another one for you, John. Alfred two
bucks, thank you very much. Um Joby
Warrick is releasing a new book
The Jackal. I know we've talked about
that here before. Were you a reference
for the book and would you consider
having him on Dead Drop to talk about
it? Uh yeah, I I was a reference for the
book. He and I talked about it as
recently as I don't know, six or eight
months ago.
And it it's funny. I've known Joby for
years. He's a He's a brilliant
journalist and a multiple Pulitzer Prize
winner. Serious like deep investigative
journalist who somehow finds the time to
bang out number one New York Times
best-selling books in his spare time. I
don't know how he does it. Research
assistant is helpful. Yeah, a good one.
A good one. Um and uh
yeah, he called me and he said that a
friend of his said that I had been
teaching this class at the University of
Salamanca and that I was spending a lot
of time talking about Carlos the Jackal.
And I said, "Yeah.
Yeah, I I have."
And um
and he said, "Well, I'm I'm doing this
book. Would you Would you talk to me
about it?" I said, "Absolutely." So we
had coffee. We spent a couple of hours
talking about Carlos the Jackal and then
he came out with his book.
He's doing well for himself, too. Good
old Joby.
Robbie, do we have an ad?
>> Hey, there's Robbie.
No. Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> I thought that would be funny way to do
it. Um Okay, so
uh
Okay, so
Um Fras Matos says, "Target shelves
empty near DC. How's the Pentagon gay
bar and pizza index looking? My money is
on a strike against Iran tonight." Ah oh
It would be a good with the weather
and all the distraction going, this
would There would be This would be a
good uh great weekend for a media dump.
Yeah, you could say that again. Um Ryan
Grim was at this dinner last night. Ryan
is from Dead Drop Media.
Very very well connected and um
somehow we got onto the topic of of Iran
and um
he said he does not expect an attack on
Iran in the next week or two, but all
bets are off once this carrier battle
group, the USS Abraham Lincoln, finally
gets to the region. He said he he does
believe that we're looking at an attack
on Iran in the coming months. Yes, I
would agree with that. Um Go to Iraq,
thanks for the 10 bucks. And I John,
this question's for you, but I would
like to chime in on it as well. What are
your rules for accepting uh Arab
hospitality? I'm not sure every random
taxi driver and shopkeeper actually
wants to host me for tea at their home,
but I'm curious. I think they actually
do, but go ahead.
They do actually and and I'll tell you
the honest-to-god's truth is I never say
no. Never. Hey, I'll tell you, the first
It's rude to say no.
It's rude to say no. Americans have a
shitty reputation as it is. It's it's
quite bad form to say no. The first time
this ever happened to me was I was in
Damascus in 1990,
I don't know, two or three.
I It was my first trip to Syria and my
boss had told me beforehand, he said
Syrians are so insular and so afraid of
their government that you will never
meet a non-official Syrian and you will
never see the inside of a Syrian's home.
So, I went to the souk
and um
and this guy asked me uh "Antwan Wayne,
where are you from?"" And I said
"I will yet to
from the United States." And he just
looked at me like
and I said "You've never met an
American, have you?"" And he said "No,
I've never met an American."
So, we stood there talking. I bought a
tablecloth that I think my ex-wife stole
from me in our divorce and um he said
"You have to come to my home. You have
to come to my home for dinner." And I
said "Oh, no, no, no, no, I don't want
to, you know, make a problem for you."
Which could have been a serious problem
for him.
He insisted and then he picked up the
phone, called his wife, closed the shop
around 9:00, we went to his house and I
still remember what a wonderful time I
had at that dinner.
Uh you know, even recently I was in What
When was I in Jerusalem in like night in
2022? Um and um
and a taxi driver invited me to his
house for dinner and dropped dropped me
off at uh
at my hotel, [snorts]
picked me up three hours later and took
me to his house for dinner.
Just in time for me to buy, you know,
some flowers for his wife and you know,
whatever. But I never say no because
they mean it. When they invite you, they
mean it. They mean it and it it's very
insulting if you say no. Like in Japan,
they don't mean it um at all. Don't say
don't say yes. If you accept it, you're
you're being an [__]
Uh but like no, in in like um
in in Wadi Rum where they filmed uh
Lawrence of Arabia in Jordan. Yes. I had
a car accident. I've been to the Wadi
Rum. I I I had a car accident. It was
bad. The car rolled into the desert. It
it was totaled. I still have the key. Um
and the uh and I went through the
windshield. And so
uh it was a it was a hell of a day and
finally the guy You went through the
windshield? I went through the
windshield. Yeah, I had like I had
safety glass all embedded in my in my in
my skull, right? I didn't know that. So,
my uh this was 2000 year 2000. This was
Actually, it's a funny story. You um it
has a connection to you maybe obliquely
um to the millennium plot. So, I was
staying at the Movenpick with my wife um
in uh on December on New Year's Eve
1999, December 31st, 1999, Y2K.
Um the Movenpick is at the entrance of
Petra and uh we, you know, we were
[__] around Petra for a couple of
days and we did the New Year's
celebration with like the British
ambassador to Jordan and all these
people and um this was before so be
later, this accident took place, but we
later learned, right, that that hotel
was targeted to be blown up by Al-Qaeda
and that night and that uh this
operation that had been disrupted by
Jordanian intelligence. Um they had a
list of like a dozen hotels they were
going to blow up all at the same time.
Um I don't know how far along it got,
but anyway, the point is it was kind of
creepy like feeling a bullet go by, you
know, by your ear or something like
Trump can probably attest. And
and uh anyway, the point is
I rolled the car in the desert and um
this guy stopped and uh this Bedouin guy
stopped in his Jeep and gave us a ride.
Uh he was like I guess part Bedouin cuz
he had a house. And he insisted that we
you know, all I wanted to do was get
back to the hotel, take [laughter] a
bath and and pull the safety glass out
of my scalp. Um but he's like "You have
to come to my house." I'm like literally
like
"Okay." And my wife's like "What the
[__] are you doing?" I'm like
"We got to. We have no choice. We have
to." That's how in That's how insistent
it is for sure. Yeah, this Syrian guy,
the only thing he asked of me was that
when I got back to Washington if I would
send him a postcard.
Which I gladly did. He just wanted to
have a postcard with a scene from
Washington, D.C.
I don't know why Tammy's talking at
referencing all the young dudes, but any
reference to Mott the Hoople, I will
take. Famously, David Bowie wrote All
the Young Dudes to save Mott the Hoople.
I freaking loved Mott the Hoople. I saw
them at GW in 1982.
They're fantastic. And Ian Hunter's solo
career is amazing. Yeah. I mean, he's
still going strong and his records are
great. I mean, you know, it's not one of
those like nostalgia things. Like if
you'd never heard of Ian Hunter and you
bought like his most recent album, you'd
be like "This is a good rock album."
Yeah, seriously. Uh
okay, so any insights on Apollo Global
Management contacts with ICE in the
government? Uh Apollo acquired
Constellis Holdings, formerly
Blackwater. This is Unsung Pat, thanks
for the 10 bucks.
I I don't know enough to answer the
question to tell you the truth. Have you
followed this? I don't know anything
about it. And by the way,
about Minnesota again, right?
Um you little bit yesterday I talked
[clears throat] about how uh you know,
general strike's not going to work in
without a broad-based left-wing
organization. But like what about I
mean,
I guess the part that's a little weird
about this is the people who are going
to suffer from all these closed
businesses are going to be Minneapolis'
economy, right? I mean, the businesses
themselves Which tells you how serious
they are about this. Yeah, but it's
almost like when there's a riot and
people burn down their own neighborhood
cuz they're pissed off at someone else.
Um
I mean, I don't know. I mean, I'm glad
they're doing something. I mean, this is
it seems like it puts the pressure
really on local politicians, but the
local politicians don't want ICE there
and we already know they don't want ICE
there. I don't know what they're
supposed to do really.
Yeah, I agree with you. Three birds, one
stone. Two bucks, thanks very much.
Where do Where do we see the world in
five years? Honest thoughts though
although optimism is not entirely off
the table. That's hilarious. You can go,
John.
>> [snorts]
>> I think that in one way or another,
we're going to be in the process of
trying to rebuild our long-standing
international friendships and
relationships.
Serious damage has been done. Serious
damage. For example, this morning,
President Trump threw the Canadians off
of the so-called peace board that uh
he's creating for Gaza like it's his to
create. Um threw the Canadians off cuz
he's angry about the speech that Prime
Minister Carney gave at uh
at Davos.
So, we've got a lot of work to do to try
to repair these relationships.
>> [snorts]
>> I mean, I think also the [clears throat]
the body politics is has never been more
divided. Um the divisions between left
and right, Democrats, Republicans, uh
the total distrust in the system. I
mean, to me it's very reminiscent of the
stuff I've read about the late Weimar
Republic and just like the there's just
like no faith whatsoever
in uh in the in the uh you know, in
representative democracy. It just feels
like it you know, nobody thinks they
care about us.
Um and that's very toxic. I mean, I
could see the system collapsing
entirely. Although frankly, I hate the
system and would love to see it
replaced. But um you know, I mean, the
problem is we don't have something
waiting in the wings to replace it.
That's all you know, whatever however
shitty your system is, it can always get
worse. Yeah. Yeah, that's right. It can
always get worse.
Yeah. Hey, did you happen to see that
the President Trump said the other day
he was talking about US-Italian
relations? Did you see this? No, I think
I missed it. He was talking about
US-Italian relations and he said that
our relations with Italy have been
excellent since Roman times.
>> [laughter]
>> And the and the translator looks at him
like "What?"
And then and then and then she
translates it.
>> [laughter]
>> It's like I don't know if he knows how
long ago that was.
>> [laughter]
>> It's like George W. Bush with the
Grecians. You know, we we love the
Grecians.
And the Greeks are like "What?"
Jesus Christ. I mean, I Okay, so I know
it's like the equivalent of like
you know, a poll tax or something, but I
kind of feel like you should have to
pass a basic history and politics test
to be allowed to run for president.
Yeah.
Yeah, I would agree. Yeah, we'd we'd
rule out pretty much almost everyone who
ever runs. So, that's That would have
that benefit. Um John, have you ever run
uh Young Courthouse wants to know and
thanks for the buck. Have you ever
uh uh crossed paths with a Jack Lee in
the 1990s?
No, I'm sorry. I can't say that I have.
Uh okay, um
the one and only Scars. Hey John, I'm in
high school and speak Arabic. Do you
recommend trying to join the CIA?
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> That's a uh
longer conversation. I'll put it this
way. If If you are inclined to join the
CIA, Mhm. um in order to make changes
from the inside,
absolutely.
You know, I
as much as I criticize the CIA and Ted
and I have talked about this a million
times,
I loved every minute of that career. I
went to 72 countries.
I met with kings and presidents and
prime ministers and had the experience
of a lifetime.
So, if you're inclined to do that kind
that kind of work knowing that you may
have to stand up one day and say, "This
is wrong and I'm not doing it and I'm
making a a whistleblower complaint."
then go for it.
The career is magnificent.
Um [snorts]
thank you for gentlemen for your work uh
and thank you for the five Canadian
dollars. Um
John, you mentioned mentioned the CIA
uses a lot of cheap gadgets from Amazon.
Then what's DARPA for? Ah, DARPA is for
the big-ticket items. The the Black
Mirror robot dogs. The the soldiers the
robot soldiers that that we're
developing now that the only reason
they're not on the battlefield fighting
is because we haven't developed a
long-life battery yet. That's what
DARPA's for. Stuff that we haven't even
thought of. But if you want to bug a
room or plant a camera or something,
just get it off of Amazon.
Um [snorts]
John, what's the website you use to
track aircraft carriers that you have
mentioned? Oh.
Let me see if I can find it again.
Uh Aaron Arnold wants to know, "Ted, do
you use a seatbelt now?"
100%.
By the way, the car that I was driving
didn't have a seatbelt.
Um
so, there is that.
Okay.
No, that wasn't the one. Oh, here it is.
Got it.
It is Yes, here it is. So, it's
it's go
www You know what? Why don't I put it in
the chat? Okay. Do you go ahead and do
that? Um Unsung Pat, wow, thanks for the
50 bucks. When it comes to the Middle
East, why don't we talk about one, the
Lord Rothschild letter, my family
created Israel. Two, the lies after
World War I that chopped up the Middle
East. Three, the 1948-1950
uh
Y um uh Y um bulk Miz child affair. I
don't know
the third one. I don't know the third
one. Um I guess maybe you can uh
elaborate on that one uh Pat, but um
you know, I I think that like in
America, you lose I have lost every
single
historical and political argument that
I've ever made that relied on someone un
either knowing history or believing that
I knew history or believing that history
was relevant to today. It just doesn't
have much effect. You know, Americans
are a-historical. I mean, and it's you
know, part of it's a superpower. We're
always looking forward. We're not
wallowing in the past. You know, we're
not pissed off about the 1389 Battle of
Kosovo. Um
but we are still um but part of the
problem is, you know, when you try to
say, "Well, this is how we The reason
it's important in my view to know how we
got here in any situation is because
then we won't make the mistake of making
the same mistake in the future and being
like, "Okay, uh you know, now
everything's solved." Like if we know,
for example, that a lot of the [__] that
Trump does is stuff that Obama did and
that Biden did and that Bush did, then
we know that these are things that, you
know, we we're not going to think that
just electing Democrats is going to
solve the Trump problem. Um but like the
point is that most people just they
can't relate to it. Not in America. This
In France or any other Greece, any other
country, you can his Russia, you can
make a historical argument and it
resonates like incredibly powerfully,
but
>> Yeah. I don't know how to get around
that. I just, you know,
I've tried it my entire life. It never
ever works and I've never see it work
with anyone else.
Yeah, I think I think you've hit that on
the head. I agree.
Um
Relaxed Garden. John, do you really
think we can repair those relationships
with our allies? I hope we can, but I'm
not sure if they'll take us seriously
anymore. I I do, actually. I do.
Um
you know, we repaired our relationships
after George W. Bush and it can be done
again. Remember that old saying that
there's no such thing as permanent
friendships, just permanent interests
and our interests are going to continue
to intersect. And so, whether we, you
know, have hurt feelings on one side or
both or not,
those those relationships will be
repaired. And some foreign leaders will
will think to themselves, "Well, that
was crazy Trump. It's better now."
Right. Exactly. Um Cat Melvin, "I hate
the system and would like to love to see
it replaced." That's me. Uh "There you
go. That's why we're doomed. Everyone
wants some kind of dramatic showdown.
It's bad." I don't want a dramatic
showdown. I just don't think this system
is reformable. Uh I would
be very clear here. You should never
have a revolution if you can avoid it.
Revolution really sucks. Um but, you
know,
if but there are there are problems that
can only be solved by revolution. Yes.
Desert Fox 41, what do you recommend
John for a history major with a poly sci
minor in their last semester at Seton
Hall?
>> [laughter]
>> This is very specific, John. Uh you
know, who is 5'9" and 120 and 147 lb uh
with brown hair. Now, about what to do
about a career. I am extremely
concerned. Um I don't know what you're
concerned about.
>> be. Don't be extremely concerned. I know
that you feel like you're under the gun,
but
don't feel bad about taking a job that
is going to end up being temporary.
You're young. You have literally a whole
lifetime ahead of you. You know, it took
it took so long for my CIA clearances to
come through, even though I was sort of,
you know, expedited through the the old
boy network. It took 18 months for my my
clearances to come through and so, I had
to take a job at the Office of Personnel
Management doing background
investigations for other people to get
their clearances. That wasn't a career.
I knew it wasn't a career. It was a
bunch of bozos just going through the
the motions of being a pretend cop. And
so, um so don't be hard on yourself. Go
ahead and take a take a temporary uh job
that you know is not going to be a
career while you do other things to
improve your your lot in life. Get a get
a graduate degree, a master's degree.
Learn a foreign language. Uh develop
another skill. Just give yourself a
little bit of time. Don't worry about
it.
Yeah. No, and also the thing is your
education can end up helping you in
unexpected ways. I have a colleague, a
cartoonist. His name uh he goes by the
name Ruben Bolling. It's not his real
name, but he does a strip called Tom the
Dancing Bug. He went to Harvard Law
School. He's never practiced law um and
I'm sure that came as a great
disappointment to his parents. He
graduated at the top of his class. He
would have been an absolutely brilliant
attorney um you know, and certainly he's
like freelanced as like a you know,
paralegal, but he's never been a lawyer.
But his cartoons are infused with that
sort of legalistic um approach and he
draws on legal knowledge for his work.
He's the only cartoonist who can do
that. Um and it shows and it might be
like one of those things like, you know,
you could read his work your entire life
and never know. But the point is it's in
there. It's part of the the the witches'
brew that makes for this magic comic
strip. Um you just never know how your
how how things are going to play out in
terms of how your ed I mean, you know, I
I I
I I went to engineering school for 3
years. I have a physics uh I have a
physics minor. I never use it, but still
it informs the way I think. The you
know, sort of the scientific method.
Like things are you know, how I
ascertain whether something is likely to
be true. That's very subtle, but you
know, it helps me in all sorts of other
in in my politics. Um Teflon money John
Don um for both of us.
Uh for viewers who may not know much
about Lebanon, how do you see the
country fitting into the Middle East
today?
Well, how I see the country fitting in
the Middle East is going to be vastly
different from how Donald Trump sees the
country fitting in the Middle East.
Because Donald Trump's view is Israel,
Israel, Israel. And you know my position
on that. I think that we have we have
very strong relations with,
you know, the the GCC countries, the
Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Bahrain, Qatar,
Oman, and the United Arab Emirates. Very
uh
good relations. I think we could do a
lot to improve our relations with with
um Algeria, Tunisia, um even Egypt.
Relations with Morocco are very good.
Lebanon's a basket case. We should be
somehow working to to, you know,
to bring the the Lebanese economy back
to life. I'm actually going to give an
interview to to a Lebanese network this
afternoon about that very issue.
And location, location, [clears throat]
location, right? Lebanon's Lebanon's
jammed up between Oh, I mean, Syria was
a bigger power, right? And
and and it will be again. Yes.
>> But Israel, Turkey, I mean, they're
surrounded by big bruisers who always
push them around. Um, on the other hand,
location, location, location, they have
a lot of shoreline, they have ports,
they have uh beautiful beaches. Um, you
know, there's potential there. There's
inherent value in Lebanon.
I mean, you know, and and
>> Agreed. I mean, as as a tourist
destination, it could be [__] off the
charts.
Yeah, without without a doubt.
I mean, speaking of which,
>> [laughter]
>> so we all remember, everybody who's
watching this show, I know has seen that
AI video that came out at the height of
the Gaza war, um of, you know, the Trump
Trump Tower Gaza, Trump Casino Gaza with
the giant gold Trump statue and all that
stuff. I used it in the thumbnail today.
Um,
do you um
you know, yesterday or 2 days ago, you
mentioned this yesterday morning, Jared
Kushner uh I guess this was yesterday
local time at Davos uh made a
presentation that kind of echoed that
leaked um uh
uh
Israeli document um that sort of had
this vision for Gaza. It's basically
full-fledged exploitation, right? It's
all rubble. We're going to we're going
to build brand new cities on over the
rubble and over the bodies of the dead
Palestinians. Um, we're going to start
from scratch. It's all going to be
glitzy and luxurious and touristy.
John, questions.
Who's going to own this land? How are
they going to get and and how will they
get it? Will they will would the
Israelis or the other you know, Western
developers who want to build there,
would they sort of go with the Maui
model or where they exploit um the
misery and and desperation of the of the
property owners to get the song to get
the the the land at a for a song and
then build there? Will the Israelis
annex it and just eminent domain it and
steal it? Um or is this just all
[__] and incapable of happening in
the same way that like the
Trans-Afghanistan Pipeline project was
never going to happen because it
required going through a war zone. Um,
you know, what's going to happen here?
I'm not sure anything is going to happen
here. Your the first thing that you said
is the I think the most important in
that
this is not our call.
We don't get to make these decisions.
We can't just It's not ours. It's not
ours and we can't pretend that
Palestinians don't live in Gaza or
shouldn't live in Gaza or won't live in
Gaza in the near future.
So that this whole this whole
>> think it's a fantasy?
I do and I think this whole peace board
or peace commissioner or whatever it is
that Donald Trump is charging people a
billion dollars to be a member of and
then just appoints his friends and
family. Um,
I just don't see how this could possibly
carry out a policy.
It would be like me just saying, you
know what uh
there's this island in Papua New Guinea.
Uh I'm going to develop it. I'm going to
charge people billion dollars to be on
my board of directors. I'm going to
develop this island. I don't own it.
I've never been there.
Uh but uh but yeah, I'm I'm going to do
this.
And then what? You expect people just to
step into line?
I just don't see it happening. Yeah, I I
does feel like they're high. Yeah.
Um Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, it's also but you know,
and then there's the politics of it,
right? I mean, how are the is how are
the Palestinians and those of us who
care about them supposed to look at
this? Um, you know, basically it's like
we're you know, you basically want to
build this shining glittering Las Vegas
on top of this giant grave the graves of
hundreds of thousands of dead Gazans.
Yeah.
>> Um and you know,
what of the people who are suffering
horribly there now that you just don't
give a [__] about? That's right.
Exactly right. I couldn't agree more.
Um we should we should before we do some
more questions, I I really want to get
your thoughts about um I thought it was
interesting that Trump um is reported in
Politico to be looking to the left for
ideas about economic populism, things
like a cap on credit card interest, um
things like coming up with a uh health
and uh you know, improve improvement on
Obamacare. And
they're saying, "Oh, he's looking to the
left rather than the right for a you
know,
to in order to address the affordability
crisis." Well, I mean, famously liberals
like to say the truth has a liberal
bias. I wouldn't say that's true. But I
will say that uh that um you know,
caring about ordinary people
economically has a left-wing bias.
Right-wingers don't get by definition.
I've just never seen an idea come out of
the Republican Party or out of the right
that addresses issues like people are
poor, they can't pay their bills, they
can't pay their rent. Um, they just
don't have ideas for that. You know,
we're still waiting for a help a real
healthcare plan.
I mean,
this puts this puts lefties into an
awkward position though, right? Like if
Elizabeth Warren works with Trump and he
ends up selling one of her ideas and and
she gets the satisfaction of seeing her
idea become come to fruition, but she's
also empowered Donald Trump and maybe
improved his chances in the midterms.
Mhm. Mhm. What do you do in a situation
like
>> do you do? Yeah.
I mean, I I mean, personally I say you
if it were me, I'd say, you know, you
take you take your you take your wins
where you can get them.
Yeah.
That's kind of my standing position.
I'm happy to form alliances
wherever I can and and take my wins.
Thanks for the 10 bucks, Waterways. Much
appreciated.
Much, much. Um, how hard is it to learn
Desert Fox wants to know. How's it hard
to learn Lebanese Arabic?
Oh, it's actually not that hard. I mean,
once you have a foundation in standard
Arabic,
many of the uh
many of the films that are made
that are broadcast all around the Middle
East are in Lebanese or Syrian dialect
and so everybody in the Middle East has
an acquaintance with them.
Psychonot,
good name. John, was there any time in
the past that the CIA used the company
as a reference to the agency or is that
just from the movie?
>> Never, ever, ever, never.
>> know they don't use this. Never.
If anybody ever said to me that they
worked for the company, I'd say, "Get
the [__] out of here, you phony."
Okay.
>> Yeah, no. That's just in the movies.
Literally no one ever in my life ever
mentioned the company.
>> right, is that the that's the name of a
famous book, right? Inside the Company.
Yeah.
Um, Cat Melvin, Bustamante told Piers
Morgan he would pretty much be doing the
same thing as Trump if he were
president. Is that reasonable? Like is
what Trump's doing strategic in any
sense? Yeah, Bustamante also said
literally on the same day in another
interview that Trump was so insane that
he and his wife and kids were leaving
the United States permanently.
So
Bustamante, the fraud that he is,
just plays to his audience. Whatever he
thinks they want to hear. He also said
in that interview with Piers Morgan, he
says, "I'm not trying to stroke you,
Piers, but your questions are sheer
genius."
>> [laughter]
>> I can't stand that guy.
Our folks 92, have you met Putin says,
"Have you read Putin's essay on the
justification for the invasion of
Ukraine? Is it a genuine example of
non-Americans caring more about history
or just retroactive justification for a
land grab?" Well, it's it's certainly
the former. I mean, you know, Putin's a
huge student of like all Russians.
Russians care about history.
Uh history's front and present for them.
Um and Putin's definitely an avid
history of he wants to make Russia great
again like like it's wants to roll like
it's 1350 all over again. Um, That is
right. Now, is that so what's so then
uh is it retroactive justification for a
land grab? Well, it's definitely just
justification, right? That's what he's
trying to do. Yes.
Obviously.
>> Yeah, that's it is. Yeah.
Um but you're right, you know, the
Sorry, no, no, we only have a minute
left. You go right ahead. No, go ahead.
I was going to say he understands
Russians in general understand history
so much better than Americans do and
they have such a longer view of issues
because their the their views are are
rooted in history. Ours are not.
Totally. Um and with that, thank you,
John, very much as always. Hope you
enjoy your weekend and that you
stay out of the snow. Um okay, so uh it
is it is now 10:00 Eastern, which means
it's time for the TMI show with me and
Medill a Chan. Please stay tuned for
that. Um we dropped a DMZ America
podcast yesterday about ICE, which
worked out really well. I highly
recommend that you go check that out.
John and I'll be back here doing
Deprogram uh at 9:00 a.m. Eastern time
and all next week on uh 9:00 a.m.
Eastern time throughout the weekdays. So
please tune in then. Have an awesome
weekend. Thank you very much and see you
see you later, John. Bye, everybody.
Bye, Ted. Bye.
>> [music]
>> Mhm.